Yingcong Tan

Contact
Information

1455 Boulevard de Maisonneuve O Montréal, QC H3G 1M8

Canada

 \boxtimes yingcong.tan@concordia.ca

⊕ https://users.encs.concordia.ca/~t_yingco/

3 Google Scholar/Yingcong Tan

• Github/Yingcong Tan

Summary

I obtained a Ph.D. in Industrial Engineering at Concordia University, under the supervision of Dr. Daria Terekhov and Dr. Andrew Delong. My Ph.D. thesis is on *Learning Linear Programs: Inverse Optimization as a Form of Machine Learning*.

I am interested in interdisciplinary research topics in Operations Research and Machine Learning. In particular, my research interests lie in inverse optimization and its applications to planning and scheduling problems.

Research Experience

Postdoctoral Fellow

Aug. 2022 - Jul.2023

TIDEL Lab, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Advisor: Dr. J. Christopher Beck, Department of Mechanical and Industrial Engineering, University of Toronto

Postdoctoral Fellow

Sep. 2021 - Jul. 2022

Concordia University, Montréal, Québec, Canada

Advisor: Dr. Daria Terekhov, Department of Mechanical, Industrial and Aerospace Engineering , Concordia University

Dr. Andrew Delong, Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, Concordia University

Research Intern

Apr. - Aug. 2021

Zhejiang Lab, Zhejiang, China

Education

Ph.D. in Industrial Engineering

Jan. 2017 - Apr. 2021

Concordia University, Montréal, Québec, Canada

Thesis: Learning Linear Programs: Inverse Optimization as a Form of Machine Learning Advisor: Dr. Daria Terekhov, MIAE Department, Concordia University Dr. Andrew Delong, CSSE Department, Concordia University

M.Eng. in Industrial Engineering

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2016

Concordia University, Montréal, Québec, Canada

Recipient of the F.A. Gerard Prize

Bachelor of Applied Science in Engineering Science

2007 - 2012

University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Major in Biomedical Engineering from the Division of Engineering Science

Refereed Conference Proceedings

Tan, Y., Delong, A., & Terekhov, D. (2020). *Learning Linear Programs from Optimal Decisions*. In Neural Information Processing Systems, 2020 (Spotlight, top 20% of the accepted papers).

Tan, Y., Delong, A., & Terekhov, D. (2019). *Deep Inverse Optimization*. Integration of Constraint Programming, Artificial Intelligence, and Operations Research, CPAIOR 2019, Thessaloniki, Greece, June 4-7 2019, (pp. 540-556).

Tan, Y., & Terekhov, D. (2018). Logic-Based Benders Decomposition for Two-Stage Flexible Flow Shop Scheduling with Unrelated Parallel Machines. In Advances in Artificial Intelligence:

31st Canadian Conference on Artificial Intelligence, CAI2018, Toronto, ON, Canada, May 8-11, 2018, (pp. 60-71).

Refereed Journal

Tan, Y., Delong, A., & Terekhov, D.. Learning the Objective of Linear Programs: Models and Insights. (In preparation).

Marzolini, S., Swardfager, W., Alter, D. A., Oh, P. I., **Tan, Y.**, & Goodman, J. M. (2015). *Quality of Life and Psychosocial Measures Influenced by Exercise Modality in Patients with Coronary Artery Disease*. European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine, 51(3), 291-299.

Referred Short Paper

Tan, Y. (2018). Automated Scheduling: Reinforcement Learning Approach to Algorithm Policy Learning. Extended Abstract. In Advances in Artificial Intelligence: 31st Canadian Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Canadian AI 2018, Toronto, ON, Canada, May 8-11, 2018, (pp. 335-338).

Conference Presentations

Tan, Y. (2020). Learning Linear Programs from Optimal Decisions.

Presentation at NeurIPS, December 6-12, 2020.

Tan, Y.(2019). Deep Inverse Optimization.

Presented at CPAIOR2019, Thessaloniki, Greece, June 4-7, 2019. Presented at JOPT2019, Montréal, Québec, Canada, May 13-15, 2019

Tan, Y. (2018). Decomposition-Based Exact Algorithms for Two-Stage Flexible Flow Shop Scheduling with Unrelated Parallel Machines.

Presented at CORS2018 Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada, June 4-7, 2018.

Presented at CAI2018, Toronto, ON, Canada, May 8-11, 2018.

Tan, Y. (2018). Automated Scheduling: Reinforcement Learning Approach to Algorithm Policy Learning.

Presentation at CAI2018 (Student Symposium), Toronto, ON, Canada, May 8-11, 2018.

Awards

Concordia Accelerator Award

2020

Concordia University, Montréal Québec

Conference and Exposition Award

2018, 2019

Concordia University, Montréal Québec

F.A. Gerard Prize 2018

Awarded annually to the most deserving non-thesis master graduate of Gina Cody School of Engineering and Computer Science

Concordia University, Montréal, Québec

Best Paper Award

2018

O.R./M.S. Scientific Writing Student Competition

GERAD, Montréal, Québec

Student Travel Scholarship

May 2018

Awarded by the student symposium of CAI2018.

Scholarships And Bursaries

Concordia Merit Scholarship

2018-2019

In-Course scholarship awarded to graduate students with high academic standing. Concordia University, Montréal, Québec

Power Corporation Of Canada Graduate Fellowship

2016-2017

In-Course scholarship awarded to graduate students with high academic standing. Concordia University, Montréal, Québec

Graduate Research Assistantship 2017-2019 Concordia University, Montréal, Québec Graduate Student Support Program Bursary 2017-2019 Concordia University, Montréal, Québec **Teaching** Teaching Assistant Experience INDU480 - Cases in Industrial Engineering (Undergraduate Course) Winter 2020 Dept. of Mechanical, Industrial and Aerospace Engineering (MIAE) Concordia University, Montréal, Québec, Canada Fall 2019 COMP6321 - Machine Learning (Graduate Course) Dept. of Computer Science and Software Engineering (CSSE) Concordia University, Montréal, Québec, Canada INDU6231 - Scheduling Theory (Graduate Course) Summer 2017 Dept. of Mechanical, Industrial and Aerospace Engineering (MIAE) Concordia University, Montréal, Québec, Canada **Professional Project Coordinator** Feb. 2013 - Aug. 2014 Experience Cardiovascular Rehabilitation and Prevention Program Toronto Rehabilitation Institute, Toronto, Ontario, Canada **Engineering Intern** Sep. 2010 - Aug. 2011 Dept. of Telecommunication Engineering Hydro One Inc., Toronto, Ontario, Canada Service Academic Reviewer Journal of Computers & Operations Research 2019 MIAE Graduate Student Committee Jan. 2016 - Apr. 2020 Dept. of Mechanical, Industrial and Aerospace Engineer Concordia University, Montréal, Quebec, Canada • Committee Chair: Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2019 • Organized graduate seminar (30+ talks); department-wide networking events (10+ events); distinguished Speaker Seminar of the Gina Cody School (4 talks); Ph.D. Student Poster Competition (3 times) • Completed several funding applications (+10K granted). Team Lead of Question Creation & Automation Sept. 2016 - Mar. 2019 The Operations Research Challenge (TORCH) Concordia University, Montréal, Quebec, Canada Clinic Exercise Volunteer Oct. 2010 - Aug. 2014 June 2012 - Feb. 2013 Research Volunteer Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation Program Toronto Rehabilitation Institute, Toronto, Ontario, Canada Certificate **CORS** Diploma 2019 Canadian Operational Research Society Graduate Seminar in University Teaching 2022 Concordia University, Montréal Québec